Hello!
Now we'd like to talk in this series about painting the exterior eaves on your house.
Now whenever you're painting exterior eaves, a couple things you want to look at.
First of all, make sure you wear a hat to kind of keep the sun off of your head and your face and some kind of sunglass.
Now, the sunglasses do 2 things.
They're going to protect any chips or paint from falling in your eyes and they're going to keep that glare out of your face because usually you're painting some kind of white or pastel because of the heavy, heavy reflection.
Now, when you're painting the eaves of your house a few things you need to consider.
First of all, how bad do they look.
If they're peeling really, really bad then you're going to want to get a really strong pressure washer on that like a gas powered one.
But if they've been painted in the last 3 or 4 years you probably just can use an electric one.
Once you've got that pressure washed, then you want to go ahead and dust that all down, do your caulking, do your spackling, and do all of your sanding.
Then once you've got that basic crepe work done, then you're going to be ready to start priming.
Once we have all of that preparation done, we'll talk a little bit about the types of paints we're going to want to choose and how to pour that paint up.
Once we've gone over that, then we're going to actually show how to apply this paint both on the interior eaves and the fascia.
Then when we're done we'll talk a little bit how to clean everything up and how to maintain this work throughout the year to have a long lasting paint job that will really beautify your house.
So when you get done with this series today you're going to know everything you need to know for painting the exterior eaves on your house.